

R. ALLAN WHITE Digital Producer

DIGITAL PRODUCER

I'm a seasoned digital craftsman, with over 20 years of experience as a designer, web developer, UX practitioner, video and event producer, and animator. I'm an intensely curious "expert generalist" who loves teaching and learning new skills.

SKILLS

Web design and development using Statamic, Expression Engine and Wordpress CMS; SASS/Compass & CSS responsive frameworks (Bootstrap, Foundation) & front-end development; back-end development and user training.

Proficient in HTML5, CSS/SASS, Javascript, Flash animation & Actionscript, Jade, Markdown, some PHP experience. Git workflow, SSH, web fonts, responsive imagery, SVG applications.

User Experience Design: This experience was a natural outgrowth of web design and client services work I've done over the years. I can help stakeholders clarify and prioritize business goals, strategy, and digital mediums through effective UX tools, written and visual documentation, wireframes, and prototypes.

Video Production: Editing, music, post-production, motion graphics & animation. Experience in workflow design, training, and asset management. Extensive mobile production experience in challenging environments in the US, Caribbean, and Africa.

Design: At the heart of what I do is the discipline of design. Art direction, branding development, logo design, typography, photography, photo-illustration, and presentation design.

Live event production: I'm a veteran of high-stakes, highpressure live events, from live webcasts, corporate and donor events, to large outdoor festivals (some with over 100,000 in attendance).

Motion graphics & multimedia: Animation & development, live event graphics, mobile & tablet web development, ebook production.

Other Specialties: Photography, writing, and non-profits.

Presentation design, public speaking, and training: A true craftsman is one who teaches and mentors others. One of my true passions is educating, training, and casting vision among clients, users and team members.

TOOLS

I have mastery of digital design tools including Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects (and plugins like Trapcode and Conduit nodal compositor), Premiere, Flash, Davinci Resolve, Final Cut Pro X, Motion, Keynote, Hype.app, iBooks Author, and live event software like Telestream and ProPresenter. Command-line? Pencil? No problem.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Digital Producer

July 2013 - Present

Independent digital craftsman and UX practitioner. Design, web development, video production, and live event media.

Digital Producer: UX, Web, Video

Luis Palau Association | Beaverton, Oregon

February 2006 - July 2013 (7 years 6 months)

Web & mobile development, user experience design, all aspects of video & motion graphics production, presentation design, event production, event photography, art direction, social media marketing.

Freelance Digital Producer

R. Allan White Design & Multimedia

June 2001 - February 2006 (4 years 9 months)

Produced and designed high-quality print, web, Flash, multimedia and video work for a variety of clients, agencies, and industries, such as:

HP EMI Music MedicaLogic Verve Records Intel Primavera Systems **Epicor** Universal Studios Copper Mountain

Rich Media Director

Strobeck Design, Inc. | Portland, Oregon

December 2001 - February 2003 (2 years)

Directed, planned, budgeted and engineered all types of audio, video, web and interactive projects. Performed high-level content development, IA, writing and editing.

Interactive Art Director

White Horse | Portland, Oregon

March 1998 - February 2001 (3 years)

Designed and directed cutting-edge media products for web, kiosk and CD. Created workflows and established assetmanagement strategies. Trained other team members in the latest tools & technologies.

EDUCATION

Harding University BFA, Graphic Design August 1991 - December 1994 Colorado State University

August 1990 - June 1991

Need a flexible, seasoned, and skilled digital producer who understands the bottom line?

Contact me today.

